{
    "1": {
        "name": "Test quiz 1",
        "subject" : "Data Structures",
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the first letter of the alphabet?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A": "Alpha",
                    "B": "B",
                    "C": "C",
                    "D": "D"
                },
                "answer": "Alpha"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the second letter of the alphabet?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A": "A",
                    "B": "B",
                    "C": "C",
                    "D": "D"
                },
                "answer": "B"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the third letter of the alphabet?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A": "A",
                    "B": "B",
                    "C": "C",
                    "D": "D"
                },
                "answer": "C"
            },
            {
                "question": "_____ is a data structure of collection of nodes which contain some data and a link to another node",
                "type": "fill_in_the_blank",
                "answer_choices": {},
                "answer": "linked list"
            }
        ]
    },
    "2": {
        "name": "Test quiz 2",
        "subject": "General CS topics",
        "questions": [
                {
                "question": "Which agents selects actions based on current precept, disregarding precept sequence?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A": "Simple reflex agent",
                    "B": "Goal-based agent",
                    "C": "Utility-based agent",
                    "D": "Model-based Agent"
                },
                "answer": "Model-based Agent"
            },
            {

                "question": "Which of the following is a linear data structure?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A": "AVL Trees",
                    "B": "Binary Trees",
                    "C": "Array",
                    "D": "Graphs"
                },
                "answer": "Array"
            },
            {
                "question": "How is the 2nd element in an array accessed based on pointer notation?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A": "*a + 2",
                    "B": "*(a+2)",
                    "C": "*(*a + 2)",
                    "D": "&(a + 2)"
                },
                "answer": "*a + 2"
            },
            {

                "question": "Which of the following algorithms are used to find the shortest path from a source node to all other nodes in a weighted graph?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A": "BFS",
                    "B": "Kruskal's Algorithm",
                    "C": "Prims Algorithm",
                    "D": "Djikstra's Algorithm"
                },
                "answer": "Djikstra's Algorithm"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following algorithms are used to find the shortest path from a source node to all other nodes in a weighted graph?",
                "type": "true_false",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "T": "True",
                    "F": "False"
                },
                "answer": "True"
            },
            {
                "question": "Binary search in a sorted array is worst case O(n)",
                "type": "true_false",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "T": "True",
                    "F": "False"
                },
                "answer": "True"
            },
            {
                "question": "The number of collisions in a hash table is solely dependent on the table capacity and the hash function",
                "type": "true_false",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "T": "True",
                    "F": "False"
                },
                "answer": "False"
            },
            {
                "question": "AVL trees and BSTs never have the same tight big-O runtime for inserting elements",
                "type": "true_false",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "T": "True",
                    "F": "False"
                },
                "answer": "False"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following standard algorithms is not Dynamic Programming based?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A":"Bellman–Ford Algorithm for single source shortest path",
                    "B":"Floyd Warshall Algorithm for all pairs shortest paths",
                    "C":"0-1 Knapsack problem",
                    "D":"Prim's Minimum Spanning Tree"
                },
                "answer": "Prim's Minimum Spanning Tree"
            },
            {
                "question": "We use dynamic programming approach when?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A":"We need an optimal solution",
                    "B":"The solution has optimal substructure",
                    "C":"The problem can be reduced to the 3-SAT problem",
                    "D":"Its faster than greedy"
                },
                "answer": "The solution has optimal substructure"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is memoization in the context of dynamic programming?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A":"A technique to write memory-efficient programs.",
                    "B":"A way to avoid solving subproblems by storing their solutions and reusing them.",
                    "C":"A process of converting recursive algorithms into iterative ones",
                    "D":"A method of analyzing the time complexity of algorithms"
                },
                "answer": "A way to avoid solving subproblems by storing their solutions and reusing them."
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following process scheduling algorithm may lead to starvation?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A":"FIFO",
                    "B":"Round Robin",
                    "C":"Shortest job Next",
                    "D":"Pick a random one"
                },
                "answer": "Shortest Job Next"
            },
            {
                "question": "If the quantum time of round robin algorithm is very large, then it is equivalent to:",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A":"FIFO",
                    "B":"Lottery Scheduling",
                    "C":"Shortest job Next",
                    "D":"None of the above"
                },
                "answer": "FIFO"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is not an optimization criterion in the design of a CPU scheduling algorithm?",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A":"Minimum CPU utilization",
                    "B":"Maximum Throughput",
                    "C":"Minimum turnaround time",
                    "D":"Minimum waiting time"
                },
                "answer": "Minimum CPU utilization"
            },
            {
                "question": "When an interrupt occurs, an operating system",
                "type": "multiple_choice",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "A":"Ignores the interrupt",
                    "B":"always changes state of interrupted process to 'blocked' and schedules another process",
                    "C":"always resumes execution of interrupted process after processing the interrupt",
                    "D":"may change the state of interrupted process to 'blocked'and schedule another process"
                },
                "answer": "may change the state of interrupted process to 'blocked'and schedule another process"
            },
            {
                "question": "________ refers to the physical parts of a computer that u can see and touch",
                "type": "fill_in_the_blank",
                "answer_choices": {},
                "answer": "hardware"
            },
            {
                "question": "________ is a process that aims to find and remove bugs from the source code of a program.",
                "type": "fill_in_the_blank",
                "answer_choices": {},
                "answer": "debugging"
            },
            {
                "question": "________ stands for integrated development environment.",
                "type": "fill_in_the_blank",
                "answer_choices": {},
                "answer": "IDE"
            },
            {
                "question": "________  is a computer program that supports the main system on a computer when it starts up.",
                "type": "fill_in_the_blank",
                "answer_choices": {},
                "answer": "kernel"
            },
            {
                "question": "________  stands for local area network.",
                "type": "fill_in_the_blank",
                "answer_choices": {},
                "answer": "lan"
            },
            {
                "question": "To find the shortest path from one vertex to another in an unweighted graph, you should use Dijkstra’s algorithm as it is the most efficient solution.",
                "type": "true_false",
                "answer_choices": {
                    "T": "True",
                    "F": "False"
                },
                "answer": "False"
            }
        ]
    }
}